Guide to the Stanford University, Committee on Black Performing Arts, Records
Stanford University. Libraries.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Stanford University, Committee on Black Performing Arts, records
1977-1990
SC1132
Stanford University. Committee on Black Performing Arts.
1.5 Linear feet (1 box)
Department of Special Collections and University Archives Green Library 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: specialcollections@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Information about Access
The materials are open for research use. Audio-visual materials are not available in original format, and must be reformatted to a digital use copy.
Scope and Contents
The materials consist of administrative records, correspondence, publications, and ephemera documenting the Committee on Black Performing Arts.
Access Terms
Richards, Sandra; Organizations, Student-General; Performing arts--California
Collection Contents
- Records
  - CBPA Archives, 2001 Nov (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Umzansi Zulu Dancers (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - In Dance Newspaper, 1989 Nov-Dec (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Talking Drums! The Black Dance Newsletter (2 copies), 1989 Nov (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Campus Report, 1997 Jan 13 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Black Theatre Conference, 1988 Jan 22-24 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Welcome Address (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Conference Notes (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - CBPA Archives, 1989-1990 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Katherine Dunham Tribute Invites, 1989 May (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - CBPA Letter Head, 1989 Jan 31 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Times Tribute, 1989 Jan 24 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Dunham in Hollywood, 1989 Jan-Feb (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Black Arts Quarterly Newspaper, 1989 Winter (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Black Arts Quarterly Newspaper, 1988 Autumn (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Dean's Office Collection, 1989-1990 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Emails to Deans, Department Admins, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Agenda/Meeting Notes, 1990 Dec. 12 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - JUBA article, 5/30/1989 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Cognizant Dean Assignments, 1989-1990 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Emails to Humanties and Science Departments, Feb. 1990 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Letters from James. N. Rosse, 1990 Feb-Jun (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Black Theatre Conference and various notes, 1987-1989 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Letters to Sandra L. Richards, 1987-988 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Black Masks Magazine Vol. 4 No. 3, 1987 Nov.-Dec. (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Trinity Performance, 1987 Nov. 19 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Black Masks Magazine Vol. 4. No. 4 (2 copies), 1988 Dec.-Jan. (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Black Masks Magazine Vol. 4 No. 1, 1987 Sept-Oct. (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Various Letters/Notes (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Datebook Newspaper Theatre/ Film Section, 1987 Dec. 20 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Press Release for John O'Neal ACE Award, 1988 Jan. 4-7 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Article on Director King, 1985 April 5 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - "Inventing the Future, Cherishing the Past" by Santiago (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - "Black Drama And Revolutionary Conciousness" by Gaffney (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - "Definition of Black Theatre" (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Emails between Stansky and Richards, 1987/1988 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Letter to Ernest D. Dillihay, 1987 Dec. 26 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Generic Panelist Letter, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Rationale: Black Theatre Conference, 1987, Sept. 9 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Black Theater: Moving Towards 21st Century, 1988, Jan. 22-24 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Conference Agenda, 1987, June 19-21 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - West Coast Theatre News, 1987 Summer/Autumn (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - "Women in the Theatre: Equality and Reality", 1987 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - "O'Neal Brings His 'Storytelling' to Stanford", 1987 Dec. 18 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - San Francisco Chronicle "Junebug" Article, 1986 June. 28 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - LA Times "Junebug" Article, 1983 March 21 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Theatre Conference Transcripts, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - University Memo, 1988 Dec 6 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Welcome Address (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - "Changing Definition of Black Theatre" by Robinson (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Keynote Address (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Aesthetics and Audience Development (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - "Bringing in the Bucks" (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Plenary Session (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Black Theatre Conference Proposal, 1986-1988 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Paid Membership roster, 1987 Aug.4 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Conference Schedule, 1988 Jan. 22-24 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Work Organizer, 1988 Jan. 22-24 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - John O'Neal Advertisements, 1988 Jan. 22-24 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - List of Contacts (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Ewart Thomas Emails, 1987 Sept. 9 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Funding Proposal, 1988 Jan. 22-24 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Interdisciplinary Minor Program Info (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Conference Official Flyer, 1988 Jan. 22-24 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Conference Expenses, 1988 Jan. 22-24 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Letters to Sandra L. Richards, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Elena Featherson Application, 1986 Sept. 8 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Invitations to Colleagues from Richards, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Program Coordinator Application From Florence Wiley, 1986 August 5 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Conference Meeting Notes, 1987 August 5 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Ethnic Minority-based Applicants List, 1985-1986 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Conference Reduced Projected Budget, 1988 Jan. 22-24 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Notes/Letters to Margaret Wilkerson, 1986-1987 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Funding Issues, 1987 Jan. 1 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Propsed Conference Workshop Topics, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Funding Propsal Draft, 11987 July 17 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Conference Flyer, 1987 May 1 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Letter to Speakers, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - California Council State of the Arts Newsletter, 1987 Sping (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Dance California Conference Agenda, 1987 June 12 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - "Centennial Projects or Events" Article, 1987 Jan. 28 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Dunham Film Retrospective, 1988-1989 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Cirriculum Vitae Yvonne Payne Daniel, 1989 Dec. (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Black Communications Workshop, 1971-1972 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Analysis of Black Musical Form (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Black Student Cultural Center (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Cultural Center Proposal, 1972 June 6 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Cinema Arts Workshop History (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Cannibal Rage (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - The Stanford Daily Volume 190 No. 26, 1986 Nov. 13 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Campus Report, 1987 April 8 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Photo of John Wilson and Barbara Cleveland with Richards (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Black Choreographers, 1988-1989 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - American Dance Festival Booklet, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - The Tribune "Out of Step" Article, 1989 Nov. 19 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Dance Columbia-One...Two...Three! Booklet, 1989-1990 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Dance Center of Columbia College Chicago Reviews and Ad, 1989-1990 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - "The Color of Identity" by Sadownick, 1989 Nov. 17-23 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - LA Times "Towards the 21st Century" Article, 1989 Nov. 21 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - S.F. Weekly Vol. 9 No. 41, 1989 Oct. 25 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - LA Times "Black Choreography", 1989 Nov. 12 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - High Performance Magazine, 1989 Spring (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - "Black Tradition in American Concert Dance" Essay (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Donald Byrd Performance History, 1988-1989 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Choreography by Joana Haigood, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - "Heat and Other Climatic Manifestations" by Sims, 1989 Spring (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Programming Ideas, 1982-1983 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Notes on budgets and ideas, 1982-1983 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Dance Week 1982 Schedule (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Dance Division Press Release, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Guest Artists, 1978-1988 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Vinnie Burrows Letters, 1983, 1988 Jan. 18-20 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Committed Artists Projects (asinamali! and Sarafina!), 1988 Feb. 25 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Reviews and advertisements for American Drama Company (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - American Drama Company of California Letter, 1986 July 11 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - "For Better Not For Worse" Play Info and Articles, 1983 Jan. 26 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - "For Better Not For Worse" Play Info Packet, 1983 Jan.-April (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Doe-Theater Suriname Information and booklet, circa 1982 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Picture and Articles about Dianne McIntyre, 1978-1980 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Black Choreographers Moving Towards the 21st Century, 1986-1989 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Notes and info about "Black Choreographers" Festival, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Festival Schedule, 1989 Nov. (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - "On the Threshold of Possibility..." Script, 1989 Nov. 8 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Publication Permission Form, 1991 Feb. 3 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Festival Artist Roster, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - "Black Choreographers Discuss Their Work" Article (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Urban Bush Women Repertory, 1986-1987 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Datebook "Black Choreographers Article" (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - In Dance Newspaper (2 copies), 1989 Nov.-Dec. (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Black Choreographers Festival Paper, 1989 Nov. 3-12 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Katherine Dunham Symposium, 1989 May 12 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Notes and schedule for Centennial Symposium, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Katherine Dunham Biography (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Dunham's Contributions to American Dance, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Financial Statement, 1989 June 22 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Various Newspaper Articles about Dunham, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - "Cultural Preservation and Positive Self-Esteem" Essay (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - "Katherine Dunham Paced the Way" Essay (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - "They Made Some 'Fierce' Daughter" by White-Dixon, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Stanford Powwow background (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - A Residency in Tribute to Katherine Dunham, 1989 May 1-27 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Press release for Dunham's Arrival, 1989 May 5 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Photo of Dunham by Dwight Carter (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - TimesTribute "Katherine Dunham", 1989 Jan. 24 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - "Dubnham Ranged from Haiti to Harlem", 1986 June 15 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Residency Info and Plans, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Stage Choreography by Dunham 1937-1972 List (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Films and Books by Dunham (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - "The Minefield" Dunham Book 3 and 2, Undated (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Dunham Symposium Publication, 1989-1990 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Estimated Expenses, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Planning Notes, 1989-1990 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - "Dunham Technique" by Rose, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Letter to Yvonne Daniel, 1989 Nov. 20 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - "Dunham and Her Contributions to American Dance", 1989 May 12 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Unity Newspaper article on Dunham, 1989 Sept. 29 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Dunham Residency Info, 1989-1990 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Newspaper articles about Dunham, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Budgetary Considerations (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Agenda, 1989 Feb. 23 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Dunham II, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Meeting Notes (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Conversations with Katherine Dunham Draft (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Letter to Dunham, 1990 May 23 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Staff Agenda, 1990 May 24 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Budget Summary, 1990 May 30-June 27 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Residency Agreement, 1988 August (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Description of work to be done for residency, 1990 April 2 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Budget Notes, Undated (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Checkoff List for Dunham Residency, 1990 April 11 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Update on Dunham residency email to Ewart Thomas, 1990 May 10 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Katherine Dunham Fellowship Budget, 1990 May 21- July 27 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Katherine Dunham Residency II Budget, 1990 May 1-July 27 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Campus Report Article about Irvine Grant, 1990 Jan. 24 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Update on Proposed Dunham II Residency, 1990 Jan. 22 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Campus Report Paper, 1989 Dec. 6 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - African and Afro-American class assignment, 1990 March 30 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Note to Laura Selznick, Undated (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Notes from Ewart Thomas Phone Call, Undated (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Meeting Agenda and notes about Dunham Project, 1990 March 5 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Budget Concerns and Info From Dean Lougee to Cashion, 1990 Feb. (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Notes about budget on Dunham, Fellowship, 1990 Feb. 1 (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Possible Source of Funding-Dunham II, Undated (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - Planning notes for Denver Conference, 1990 Jan. 1 (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - Fellowship Information, Undated (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - Estimated Expenses for Dunham Symposium Papers, 1990 Jan. 18 (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - Fellowship for Dunham Notes and Info, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - "The Minefield" Dunham Prologue, 1937-1947 (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - Essay about Dunham's arrival at Stanford, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - The Proposed Dunham Residency: Provisional Proposal, 1989 Dec. 11 (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - Dunham Residency Documentary Info, 1989 Dec. 14 (Box 1, Folder 51)
  - Info on Fellowships, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 52)
  - "A Report on the Katherine Dunham Residency", 1989 July 18 (Box 1, Folder 52)
  - Notes on Dunham Publication, Scheduling, and Reception, 1989 Dec. 11 (Box 1, Folder 53)
  - Notes about funding proposal and newsletter, 1989 Dec. 11 (Box 1, Folder 54)
  - Email about Proposed Dunham Residency II: Notes, 1989 Oct. 16 (Box 1, Folder 55)
  - Agenda Notes, 1989 Dec. 8 (Box 1, Folder 56)
  - Dunham Residency Video Documentary Info, 1989 Nov. 29 (Box 1, Folder 57)
  - Suggested Readings on World Dance, 1989 Fall (Box 1, Folder 58)
  - Dunham Residency Meeting Notes for Halifu, 1989 Nov. 28 (Box 1, Folder 59)
  - Katherine Dunham II Notes, 1989 Nov. 27 (Box 1, Folder 60)
  - Yvonne Payne Daniel Curriculum Vitae, 1989 May (Box 1, Folder 61)
  - Katherine Dunham Symposium Final Program, 1989 May 12 (Box 1, Folder 62)
  - Letters to Yvonne Daniel about Symposium, 1989 May-June (Box 1, Folder 63)
  - Dunham Centennial Symposium Financial Statement, Undated (Box 1, Folder 64)
  - Proposed Dunham Residency Prt. 2 Email to Halifu, 1989 Oct. 8 (Box 1, Folder 65)
  - email about Request for Future Residencies, 1989 July 25 (Box 1, Folder 66)
  - Dunham II CBPA notes, 1989 July 24 (Box 1, Folder 67)
  - Recommendation for CBPA budget and Dunham Residency, 1990 Feb. 2 (Box 1, Folder 68)
  - Possible Financial Scenario for Dunham Projects, Undated (Box 1, Folder 69)
  - Resident Artists Program Application, (No year) Dec. 12 (Box 1, Folder 70)
  - Announcement of External Faculty Fellowships, 1990-1991 (Box 1, Folder 71)
  - CBPA Vision Statements, 1987-1988 (Box 1, Folder 72)
  - Visions Statement for CBPA, 1987 Nov. (Box 1, Folder 72)
  - Update to Vision Statement, 1988 June (Box 1, Folder 72)
  - Black Arts Quarterly, 1988-1989 (Box 1, Folder 73)
  - Various Black Arts Quarterly Newspapers, 1988-1989 (Box 1, Folder 73)
  - Negro Ensemble Company (Box 1, Folder 74)
  - "Ceremonies in Dark Old Men" Reviews, 1986 Fall (Box 1, Folder 74)
  - 15th Annual Notes, 1987-1989 (Box 1, Folder 75)
  - "Festival Works to Save Pioneering Dances" Article (Box 1, Folder 75)
  - "Moving Toward the 21st Century" Theater Artaud Paper, 1989 Nov. 3-12 (Box 1, Folder 75)
  - Notes about CBPA 15th Annual (Box 1, Folder 75)
  - Margaret b. Wilkerson biographical Sketch, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 75)
  - Dunham Invites, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 76)
  - Drama Office Theatre Conference Materials, 1980-1988 (Box 1, Folder 77)
  - "Black Theatre Artists Convene at Stanford" Article (Box 1, Folder 77)
  - "Casting: Beyond Tradition" by Fichandler (Box 1, Folder 77)
  - Conference Letter, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 77)
  - "Black Theatre in California: An Observation", 1980 (Box 1, Folder 77)
  - Letters from conference supporters, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 77)
  - "Moving Towards the 21st Century" Info Flyers, 1988 Jan. 22-24 (Box 1, Folder 77)
  - Theatre Projects (Box 1, Folder 77)
  - Beverly Robinson Speech on "Who Are We?" (Box 1, Folder 77)
  - Stanford Centennial Celebration Activities and Conference, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 77)
  - Searches: CBPA/AAAS, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 78)
  - Drama Performing Arts Replacement Info, 1990 Feb 13 (Box 1, Folder 78)
  - List of possible replacements, 1990 Feb (Box 1, Folder 78)
  - Future of CBPA (Box 1, Folder 78)
  - AAAS Undergrad Scholars, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 79)
  - Candidates List and Letters (Box 1, Folder 79)
  - U.S.P. paper by Nathaniel Crowell, 1987 June 6 (Box 1, Folder 79)
  - List of first members of Undergraduate Scholars Program, 1987 March 18 (Box 1, Folder 79)
  - "Sounds in Motion" Info, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 80)
  - Pictures from "Sounds in Motion" (Box 1, Folder 80)
  - "Sounds in Motion" Rehearsal Schedule, 1977-1978 (Box 1, Folder 80)
  - "Sounds in Motion" reviews, 1980-1981 (Box 1, Folder 80)
  - Notes and Planning Calendar, 1983-1984 (Box 1, Folder 80)
  - Stanford Drama "Spell #7" Synopsis (3 copies), 1984 Feb. 1-4, 8-11 (Box 1, Folder 81)
  - Stanford Newspaper "Black Students", Undated (Box 1, Folder 82)
  - Memorandum Essays, 1989-1990 (Box 1, Folder 83)
  - "Katherine Dunham's Choreography, 1938-1987" by Clark (Box 1, Folder 83)
  - "Dunham as a Cultural Theorist" by Creque-Harris, 1990 March 16 (Box 1, Folder 83)
  - Centennial Symposium Draft, 1989 May 12 (Box 1, Folder 83)
  - "The Minefield" Dunham Book I and II, Undated (Box 1, Folder 84)